Matheus Gomes de Paula

Parana, Brazil

SUMMARY

Matheus Gomes is a Brazilian creator, mentor and programmer. He currently lives in Foz do Iguaçu, Brasil. His lifelong appreciation for building software and sharing knowledge led him to write articles that impacted 70 thousand people worldwide. Matheus developed multiple applications, mentored students, and worked at major companies in Latin America and North America, such as Agrotools, 3 Corações, BuildingLink and UCLA.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Intive (BuildingLink) | New York, NY | May 2023 - April 2024

- Designed and implemented key features aimed at improving software functionality and **enhancing** user experience. Notable enhancements included an Event Log functionality, providing users with a comprehensive record of system activities for improved transparency and accountability.
- Additionally, introduced a filtered group of functionalities, streamlining user interactions and navigation by categorizing features based on type. These **enhancements** incorporated essential concepts such as **user types**, **authorization** mechanisms, **image uploading** capabilities, and streamlined **form handling** processes, resulting in a more intuitive and efficient software experience.
- · Working with Vue 3, Jest, Typescript, Storybook, Linux, and other modern technologies.

Software Engineer | CUROTEC (UCLA - PAIRIN) | Los Angeles, USA | April 2022 - May 2023

- · Collaborated with UCLA to create a new library access page using modern technologies such as Vue 2, Rollup, Nuxt, Storybook, Cypress, Git, GraphQL, PHP, Laravel, Docker, and React with Redux.
- Implemented a rigorous development workflow, including conducting automated tests with **Cypress**, performing thorough code reviews with an average of 3 reviews per pull request, and engaging in pair programming sessions for critical features.
- Developed a reusable, and with responsive design, a component library using Rollup and Vue 2, resulting in a library of 50+ components utilized across different applications. Those components were tailored by Designers in our New York team.
- Led the implementation of the component library project as the sole Brazilian member in a diverse team of 10, delivering the project within the agreed-upon timeline and achieving a 95% satisfaction rating from the team members. The projects are available in the UCLA library website and PAIRIN website.
- Designed, developed, and maintained software applications for talent assessment and development products, resulting in a 20% increase in product performance and a 15% reduction in bug reports. The products were created using some modern tech such as Craft CMS, GraphQL and Next Js with Redux.
- Engineered 15 new features, resolved 50+ bugs, and optimized software resulting in a 30% improvement in response time.
- Improved user experience by enhancing the site's sidebar, optimizing mobile responsiveness resulting in an increase in **mobile user experience**, and ensuring scalability and **accessibility** color contrast criteria compliance, meeting **WCAG 2.0 AA standards**.

Sr. Software Engineer | PWR Pixel | São José dos Campos, SP - Brazil | June 2021 - April 2022

- Delivered specialized front-end consulting services to resolve complex challenges in notable corporations such as **3 Corações**, alongside various startups including GlobalPro Fit and Codex, among others.
- Activities provided involve improving an application by **50% of loading performance**. **Code reduction by 75%** with the application of clean code and good practices. Introduction of code patterns for both commit and development. Also, having active participation in code review and hiring of new developers.
- · Acted as a team leader for a global and remote development team, providing training and writing documentation for the new developers.
- · Worked with Vue with Vuex and Vue Router, pug, React with Redux and Material UI, and Jest/Vitest.

Full Stack Developer | Spread Tecnologia | São Paulo, SP | April 2021 - June 2021

- · Collaborated with industry-leading clients, such as Petrobras and Qualicorp, to deliver custom chatbots for WhatsApp using Node.js and Express.js.
- · Provided technical expertise and guidance to support junior team members.

Lead Front End Engineer | Pixfy | Jacareí, SP - Brazil | June 2020 - May 2021

- · Led the front-end team at Pixfy, delivering and conducting projects for **startups**, **ONGs**, and other companies.
- · Designed and built entire projects with **VueJs**, **SASS**, and other modern technologies.
- Designed a website project with **AdobeXd** for an electrical engineering company.

Backend Developer | Ânima Educação | São Paulo, SP - Brazil | October 2020 - April 2021

- Development of **APIs** in .**NET Core** for the **Ânima** institution and applied better ways to develop using **Gitflow** and **writing articles** and **documentation** for internal use, impacting every new developer.
- · Used design patterns such as DDD and Implemented software principles such as **SOLID** and **Clean Code**, used by the whole squad.
- · Carried out the implementation of modern technologies such as **Xunity** (.NET Core), delivering value and unit testing.
- · Tech used consisted of Relational Databases with **SQL** and Oracle DB.

Full Stack Developer | Agrotools | São José dos Campos, SP - Brazil | July 2020 - October 2020

- · Carried out the development of mobile applications using **React-Native and C#**.
- Helped the Innovation team using **React with redux** and **Vue with vuex**, also helped develop new features using **JavaScript Vanilla and .NET.** Some of the features were related to Web Performance Optimization and Asynchronous State Management, all using lighthouse and Hooks in this Unified Platform for the agtech.
- · Directly involved in learning and using SCRUM in his team. Making the integration of good practices and maintenance excellence.

Full stack Intern | Agrotools | São José dos Campos, SP - Brazil | October 2018 - July 2020

- · Carried out the application development using Javascript, Jquery, and also modern frameworks including Vue.js React and Sass.
- · Implemented a translation resource (i18n) in insurance service and the creation of HTTP routes in RESTFUL APIs in C # .NET.
- · Carried out the development of tools using map services (**Open Layers**).
- Researched and developed tools that facilitate the creation of queries at the first user level and the developer level, resulting in a decrease in time to build **SQL** queries.

SKILLS

Javascript and modern JS Frameworks (Vue2, Vue3), Web Design (Adobe XD, Figma), PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, and preprocessors (SCSS), Agile (SCRUM), Jest, Git, NuxtJS, Element UI, Bootstrap, Vuetify, Cypress, GraphQL, Storybook, Typescript, NextJs, React, React-native, Pinia, Vuex, Vue Router, Axios, Material UI, Node.

PROJECTS

Web Content Writer | dev.to | Medium | mgodev.hashnode.dev | April 2022 - Present

- · Writing tutorials on emerging technologies in English that received more than 50 thousand views on the posts.
- · Also writing technology news on cryptocurrencies and blockchain for the website bitnoticias.
- · Also writing about philosophy, religion, and stoicism in my free time.

Researcher | UDC - Centro Universitário Dinâmica das Cataratas | January 2024 - April 2024

- · Developed a mobile application leveraging acoustic audio data from heart and lung sounds to assist medical professionals in diagnosing health issues.
- The app shows the audios and adds valuable insights to doctors and nurses during the diagnostic process. This groundbreaking **research** project aimed to enhance the efficiency and accuracy of medical diagnostics, ultimately contributing to improved patient care and outcomes.
- · The research intends to be published in a scientific magazine.

Mentor | ODONA | September 2022 - February 2023

- Front-end technology **mentor** for diverse niches of people belonging to underrepresented groups. Such as black people, indigenous people, people who identify with the female gender, people with disabilities, people residing in peripheral regions, and LGBTQIA+ people.
- · Provided 1-on-1 and group mentorship sessions to help underrepresented individuals advance skills in the technology industry.

Researcher | UNIFESP | March 2021 - September 2022

- · Conducted and developed a front-end application that acted as a form for restaurant research at **UNIFESP**.
- · Using Vue 2, Sass, Element UI, and also Vercel.
- · Conducting the development as a **leader** of a small team of front-end developers.

Book Writer - Guia Markdown | November 2021 - November 2021

- \cdot Wrote an e-book all about Markdown, with the help of two editors in three months.
- · The e-book remains free, enabling everyone to enjoy the benefits offered.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ View the book on my LinkedIn Profile or on my website.

AWARDS

Hackathon Call For Code | IBM | August 2020

• Placed at 4th place in Latin America, 2nd place Brazil, in the IBM hackathon - Call for Code by developing an application to solve the problem of COVID-19 in the world. The app notifies users potentially exposed to COVID-19 anonymously, securely, and in a way that respects the individual's privacy.

EDUCATION

Master of Business and Administration (MBA) in Entrepreneurship and Innovation | Universidade Cruzeiro Do Sul | São Paulo, Brasil | 2024

Graduate degree in Data Science | Universidade Descomplica | São Paulo, Brasil | 2024

Bachelor of Science and Technology | Federal University of São Paulo | São José dos Campos, SP - Brazil | 2022